<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Pietschmann</title>
    <description>I have more than 20 years of experience in the Software Development industry that includes working as a Consultant and Trainer in a wide array of different industries. Welcome to my resume and work history portfolio website!
</description>
    <link>http://pietschsoft.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://pietschsoft.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:16:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:16:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>JavaScript: AG-Grid + ASP.NET MVC Infinite Row Model DataSource with Entity Framework</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;AG-Grid supports infinite scrolling through the use of it’s support for implementing Infinite Row Model. This allows for the grid to lazy-load rows of data from the server depending on the scroll position of the data grid. Essentially, it loads the first page of results, then as the user scrolls, it loads more data as they continue to scroll down through the list. It allows you to implement a more desktop app style data table interface in your web applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2023/08/18/javascript-aspnet-mvc-aggrid-infinite-row-model-datasource</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2023/08/18/javascript-aspnet-mvc-aggrid-infinite-row-model-datasource</guid>
        
        <category>JavaScript</category>
        
        <category>js</category>
        
        <category>EntityFramework</category>
        
        <category>EF</category>
        
        <category>AG-Grid</category>
        
        
        <category>JavaScript</category>
        
        <category>ASP.NET MVC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Fitness Journey Challenges and Successes and Tony Horton as my Personal Trainer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not wealthy or a celebrity, but Tony Horton is my personal trainer. It all started way back in 2010. I was out of shape, unhealthy, and didn’t want to be a let down for my baby girl. I found out about this “workout at home” program called P90X made by Tony Horton and Beachbody. I even came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamripped.com/my-story/&quot;&gt;Coach Wayne’s success story&lt;/a&gt;, and I thought, “This could help me. This could actually work!” So I bought in and purchased the P90X workout program, a couple dumbbells, and went all in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2023/03/09/My-Fitness-Journey-Challenges-and-Successes-and-Tony-Horton-as-my-Personal-Trainer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2023/03/09/My-Fitness-Journey-Challenges-and-Successes-and-Tony-Horton-as-my-Personal-Trainer</guid>
        
        <category>Fitness</category>
        
        <category>P90X</category>
        
        <category>Beachbody</category>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Gym</category>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>JavaScript Fundamentals: Variables, Arrays, and Loops</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is a powerful and versatile programming language that is widely used for web development. As a beginner in JavaScript, it is important to have a solid understanding of the basics, including variables, arrays, and loops. In this article, we will dive into these essential concepts and provide practical examples and exercises to help you master them. Whether you’re new to coding or just looking to refresh your skills, this article is designed to be a comprehensive guide for learning the fundamentals of JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2023/02/04/javascript-fundamentals-variables-arrays-loops</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2023/02/04/javascript-fundamentals-variables-arrays-loops</guid>
        
        <category>JavaScript</category>
        
        <category>js</category>
        
        
        <category>JavaScript</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top Terraform and Azure Articles on Build5Nines in 2022 (plus year in review)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to write up summary posts about the traffic of &lt;a href=&quot;https://build5nines.com&quot;&gt;Build5Nines.com&lt;/a&gt; over on Build5nines.com. It’s been a few years since I did a write up of the annual traffic over there, so I decided to write up a simplified version of the old “Build5Nines.com year in review” style posts for 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2023/01/11/top-terraform-azure-articles-on-build5nines-in-2022</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2023/01/11/top-terraform-azure-articles-on-build5nines-in-2022</guid>
        
        <category>Terraform</category>
        
        <category>Azure</category>
        
        <category>DevOps</category>
        
        <category>SRE</category>
        
        
        <category>DevOps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is ChatGPT and is it important?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT seems to be the buzz and is talked about everywhere across social media today. Specifically, ChatGPT that is a variant of GPT-3 language model that provides an artificial intelligence (AI) chat bot. People are using it to write college essays, programming code, and many other things. I decided to take a look at it, try it out, and ask it some questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/12/14/what-is-chatgpt-and-is-it-important</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/12/14/what-is-chatgpt-and-is-it-important</guid>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>OpenAI</category>
        
        <category>ChatGPT</category>
        
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Workflow for Build5Nines Weekly Newsletter Generation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For about 7 years now I’ve been publishing a weekly newsletter that goes along with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://Build5Nines.com&quot;&gt;https://Build5Nines.com&lt;/a&gt; website / blog. It’s a weekly newsletter that you can sign up with your email address to receive weekly updates on the latest news and blogs in the community around Microsoft cloud technologies. If you aren’t aware, Build5Nines is a website / blog that’s dedicated to many topic areas around Microsoft cloud technologies. At the moment the newsletter has approximately 12,000 email subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/10/26/my-newsletter-workflow-for-build5nines-weekly-generation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/10/26/my-newsletter-workflow-for-build5nines-weekly-generation</guid>
        
        <category>Blogging</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
        <category>Consulting</category>
        
        <category>Authority</category>
        
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
        <category>Blogging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Always Focus on What Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So often in life we get distracted. These distractions can come in many forms. Sometimes things happen that distract our attention unnecessarily, like friends / family wanting our attention or something breaks that needs attention. Other times, we distract ourselves since we don’t want to deal with the realities of life. What ever the distraction is, it’s important to not allow it to pull your focus away from the important things for too long. Sure, there are times when we a distraction is welcome, but it mustn’t be allowed to persist for too long.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/10/07/always-focus-on-what-matters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/10/07/always-focus-on-what-matters</guid>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        <category>Personal</category>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
        <category>Personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Work Authoring Microsoft Cloud Workshops</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last several years, I’ve been involved with writing content for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://microsoftcloudworkshop.com&quot;&gt;Microsoft Cloud Workshops&lt;/a&gt; (MCWs). These contain design sessions and hands-on lab training content that Microsoft uses to train their own Cloud Solution Architects (CSAs) and even used when working with customers to teach more about deploying advanced Microsoft Azure workloads in the cloud. I have authored new MCWs myself, as well as worked to help update and maintain many of the existing MCWs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/09/13/my-work-authoring-microsoft-cloud-workshops</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/09/13/my-work-authoring-microsoft-cloud-workshops</guid>
        
        <category>Work</category>
        
        <category>MCW</category>
        
        <category>Training</category>
        
        
        <category>Work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Ranks Active Blogs Higher is Search Results</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I figured out recently that Google does factor in how active your site or blog is when ranking content in the search results. In the SEO world, there’s a ton of recommendations on keyword research and how to write the perfect articles. However, what no body talks about is whether a blog or website being active in publishing new content has an affect on the traffic that will be sent to it by Google through organic searches. I found out recently with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://Build5Nines.com&quot;&gt;https://Build5Nines.com&lt;/a&gt; website that Google does take into account how active your website is in how it will rank that websites content in search.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/09/06/google-ranks-active-blogs-higher-in-search-results</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/09/06/google-ranks-active-blogs-higher-in-search-results</guid>
        
        <category>Blogging</category>
        
        <category>SEO</category>
        
        <category>Authority</category>
        
        
        <category>Blogging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>JavaScript: Remove Specific Items from Array</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When writing JavaScript code, there are many use cases where working with Arrays is required. Creating arrays of values / object and receiving them from API calls is really common. &lt;a href=&quot;/post/2020/07/01/loop-through-javascript-arrays-using-for-forEach-map-functions&quot;&gt;Looping through JavaScript Arrays&lt;/a&gt; is a common action to perform, but removing items from a JavaScript Array you are working with is not as straight forward. In this article, we’ll take a look at some methods that can be performed to allow you to make sense of removing items from an array.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 19:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/08/13/javascript-remove-item-from-array</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://pietschsoft.com//post/2022/08/13/javascript-remove-item-from-array</guid>
        
        <category>JavaScript</category>
        
        <category>js</category>
        
        
        <category>JavaScript</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
